PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A high-energy student currently finalizing bachelor's degree in Computer Science and prepared to contribute abilities to full time role while further developing acquired skills and gaining real-world experience. Highly organized, responsible and well-versed in Java and C++.Positively impact Machine Learning, Web Development and Big Data operations with top-notch communication and critical thinking skills.

WORK HISTORY

Ezbiz Technologies Pvt Ltd (Noida) – Internship (Jun 2019 – Jul 2019)

- Maximized strategic approaches by keeping close eye on performance and adjusting based on market trends
- Updated quality control standards, methods and procedures to meet compliance requirements of the clients
- Supported marketing programs and campaigns with content and messaging to drive demand of the company

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

SMO using MapReduce: Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

- Github Repository
- Parallelization of Spider Monkey Optimization Algorithm is performed to get better and more accurate results when dealing with huge amount of data in less time
- Random initialization of the population variables is done, and other decision variables are used to determine the results
- Platform used: Hadoop along with HDFS (Hadoop Distributed File System), MapReduce architecture and Python

THE THIRD EYE: Jul 2019 - Jan 2020

- Github Repository
- Project to simplify the lives of visually impaired people by helping them to live their dream life
- Trained the model based on Inception v4 methodology on a dataset
- Created a web-app using Tensorflow.js which helped in implementing the trained model

STRING PLAYGROUND: Feb 2019 - Apr 2019

- Github Repository
- Image classification is applied for string recognition and then the text recognized is subjected to string matching algorithms like KMP algorithm, etc.
- Python is used for the code and keras library for image recognition and then tested on MNNIST dataset

FRIEND FINDER: Oct 2018 - Dec 2018

- Github Repository
- A social media website consisting of special features like friend suggestions, posting pictures or videos It included the algorithm of predicting "People you may know" through user's friend list
- Developed using CSS, PHP, JAVASCRIPT and then run and tested on XAMPP server.

PAYTEZZ: Aug 2018 - Oct 2018

- Github Repository
- An e-wallet with features like checking bank-balance, two-tier security for every transaction, adding or paying money to another user, etc.
- Coded using C++ while using FILE as the data structure to store all data requirements

SKILLS

- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Machine Learning
- Data Analytics
- C/C++ Programming
- Java
- Python
- HTML, JavaScript, PHP, CSS, Bootstrap
- Database Management System (DBMS) and SQL
- Hadoop, MapReduce Programing
- Natural Language Processing (NLP)
- OpenCV
- Linux
- English Proficiency

EDUCATION

TRAINING - ADVANCE JAVA

Bestech Solutions (Prayagraj) – (Jun 2018 - Jun 2018)

 One-month training on all aspects of advanced java including frameworks.

TRAINING – WEB DEVELOPMENT Internshala (Online) – (May 2020 – Jun 2020)

- Certificate link
- 6 weeks online course consisting of HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, SQL and PHP modules

B. Tech (Hons.), Computer Science (2017 - 2021) JAYPEE INSTITUTE OF INFORMATIONTECHNOLOGY

• CGPA: 8.50/10

XII (Senior Secondary), Science Year of Completion: 2017

ISC Board (Boys' High School and College, Allahabad)

Percentage: 89.50%

X (Secondary)

Year of Completion: 2015

ICSE Board (Boys' High School and College, Allahabad)

Percentage: 93.00%

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Attended TCS iON's 'Career Edge Knockdown the Lockdown' online course. <u>Certificate Link</u>
- Completed JP Morgan's Software Engineering Virtual Experience internship. <u>Certificate Link</u>